Guide to the Student Aid Foundation Enterprises C.D. Broad Exchange materials, 1962-2016 UA 399
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
Student Aid Foundation Enterprises C.D. Broad Exchange materials
1962-2016
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Rice University.
UA 399
0.5 Linear Feet 1 box
This collection consists of paperwork, slides, newsclippings, photographs, speeches, and paraphernalia relating to the C.D. Broad Exchange between Rice University and Trinity College, Cambridge.
Historical Note
The C.D. Broad exchange program started as the brainchild of Frank Abraham, founder of the Abraham Student Aid Foundation Inc., who had attended Trinity College, Cambridge in his youth and felt that an exchange between the renowned British college and Rice University would be a worthwhile project to support. Originally intended to be a three-year direct exchange program, the foundation ended up sending one student overseas at a time with the United States and England alternating as host every year from 1962 to present day.
The first exchange was between G. Lindsey Buchanan, 21-year-old graduate of Cambridge University, and James Sears McGee, 19-year-old Rice student. Though he stayed in a dormitory during his time at Rice, Lindsey was hosted by the McGees while he studied Industrial Management.
Scope and Contents
This holding consists of paperwork, slides, newsclippings, photographs, speeches, and paraphernalia relating to the C.D. Broad Exchange between Rice University and Trinity College, Cambridge. Copies of some materials are also contained on a CD.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Stored off-site at the Library Service Center. Please request this material via woodson@rice.edu or call 713-348-2586.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
These materials were transferred to the archives in 2018.
Index Terms
Subjects
Student exchange programs; Universities and colleges
Places
Rice University
- Series I: Early Exchange Materials
  - Memorabilia: Street Guide, Honor System Book, Activity Card, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Portraits, circa 1962 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Newsclippings, 1962-1980 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Scrapbook Pages (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Series II: Later Years and Reunions
  - Speeches and Remarks, 1992 - 2003 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Exchange Program Papers, 2011 - 2016 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Printed Slides (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - CD with original pictures, scans, slides (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Three-ring Binder: "C.D. Broad Exchange between Rice University and Trinity College" (Box 1)